<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Trenton Pulsipher</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Trenton Pulsipher</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ancestry Product Analytics Homework Assignment</title>
      <link>/post/ancestry-product-analytics-homework-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ancestry-product-analytics-homework-assignment/</guid>
      <description>The homework assignment document shared with me contained the following questions:
Define the problem: What is the cross-sell status today based on the dataset? For example, what fraction of the observed users cross-sell to subscription? Perform any cleaning, exploratory analysis, and/or visualizations to use the provided data for this analysis (a few sentences/plots describing your approach will suffice). Discuss your analytics plan/steps to derive insights, identify opportunities, and recommend any optimization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stock Prices</title>
      <link>/post/stock_prices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/stock_prices/</guid>
      <description>Stock Prices App
The link above will take you to my shinyapps.io page where I have deployed a R/Shiny app. The app is rough and basic and reflects only a few hours of my time (1&amp;frasl;2 day) to make, but should meet the requirements - especially if you imagine all the variations available and noted at the bottom of this post.
The left portion of the app allows the user to select the stock ticker of interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>resume</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>Employment Henry Schein One
Sr Data Scientist (American Fork, UT) Apr 2017 - Present
As the lone data scientist at Henry Schein One I lead efforts to build predictive modeling via machine learning algorithms, promote data governance and business process documentation, and regularly share analytical best practices.
Created web-based tools to share statistical modeling visualizations with the sales, customer success, and marketing teams internally. Built in Linux, these analytical tools allow for sharing of interactive JavaScript based apps via HTML pages in an R markdown/blogdown/Hugo generated website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I’m a data scientist / statistician with over 10 years of experience analyzing everything from customer attrition to ovarian cancer biomarkers to weather modeling to protein pKa predictions to power grid load demand to organic lettuce sales. I primarily use R, which enables me to use RMarkdown, various wrappers for JavaScript plotting libraries (rBokeh, Leaflet, trelliscopejs, etc.), and an appropriate backend like Hadoop or Spark.
Outside of work I try to enjoy supporting my wife in our effort to fix up our small old house while pretending to be country farmers on our acre property (lots of fruit and nut trees, and chickens).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>